Register of the Delos Carleton Emmons Papers, 1904-1951.
Hoover Institution Archives
Delos Carleton Emmons Papers
1904-1951
69019
Emmons, Delos C. (Delos Carleton), 1888-1965.
1 manuscript box (.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, and orders, relating to the U.S. military mission to Great Britain in 1940, and to U.S. troops stationed in Hawaii and on the U.S. Pacific coast during World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Air Force--Officers.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Great Britain.; World War, 1939-1945--Hawaii.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; Great Britain.; Hawaii.; United States--Armed Forces.
Container List
- Container List
  - Correspondence: Official and unofficial, 1939-1948 (including papers regarding relinquishment of Western Defense Command). (Box 1.)
  - Correspondence: Appointments - Retirement, 1904-1951.
  - Orders of Emmons' (personal, special, general).
  - Correspondence: miscellaneous, unofficial and official (list of persons included in front of folder; includes Nimitz, Chester W.; Hurley, Patrick; Eisenhower, Dwight D.; Stimson, Henry L; Spruance, Raymond A.; Woodring, Harry; Wei, Li-huang; Symington, W. Stuart; Lattimore, Owen; Rickenbacker, Eddie; Richardson, Robert C.
  - Miscellaneous notes (29 pp.) on U.S. Military Mission to the United Kingdom (1940), headed by Emmons.
  - Midway Island - Official Reports (confidential, secret) and two letters regarding Midway.
  - Report on National Defense Agencies: use of Army Air Force (30 pp.). Prepared about 1939?
  - Telegrams: Official 1942-46, military matters, martial law in Hawaii.
  - Marshall, Gen. George C. - correspondence from Marshall, 1940-44.
  - Correspondence:
    - a. Brazilian flight
    - b. Appointment - congratulations
    - c. Decorations and commendations
  - Correspondence - clippings Martial Law in Hawaii.
  - Correspondence - miscellanea Martial Law in Hawaii.
  - Correspondence and notes re Emmons' departure from Hawaii.